#### Contact

hi@henrystoll.de

www.linkedin.com/in/henry-stoll (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Conversational Al Infrastructure as code (IaC) LangChain

### Languages

German (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

# Henry Stoll

GenAl Engineer @Danske Bank | Data Science | CBS

Copenhagen, Capital Region of Denmark, Denmark

## Summary

Data scientist with a passion for turning data into insights that help people and businesses make better decisions. I have a strong interests in machine learning, NLP and data strategy and enjoy working with data of all types. I'm also an experienced software engineer, which gives me the ability to build data-driven applications and products.

# Experience

Danske Bank Senior Data Scientist September 2024 - Present (7 months) Copenhagen, Denmark

GenAl Engineering

UNHCR, the UN Refugee Agency Data Scientist (NLP Specialist) May 2023 - March 2024 (11 months) Copenhagen, Capital Region, Denmark

Building scalable media classifiers using Llama2, Mistral and BERT models in the context of hate speech and anti-refugees sentiment on social media. Created a highly scalable MLOps architecture to process thousands of posts per minute in production on AWS and GCP using Infrastructure as Code (IaC). Prototyped chatbots and internal tools using commercial LLMs like GPT4, Vertex and AWS Bedrock. Supervised the creation of multiple innovative high quality large multilingual abusive speech datasets.

rapidcreative.io
Technical Advisor
January 2023 - March 2023 (3 months)
Copenhagen

Built and validated a chatbot for turning text into short videos using GPT4, RAG, langchain and React.

#### UNICEF

Technology Consultant July 2021 - January 2023 (1 year 7 months)

Copenhagen, Capital Region, Denmark

Technical lead for a pilot project to increase supply chain visibility for worldwide NGO partners using blockchain. The Last Mile Supply Monitoring Project aims to better understand how for example schools, hospitals and children benefit from UNICEF's supply programmes through data outside of UNICEF's current systems. The app is piloted in 10 different countries, with onsite visits in Lebanon, with the goal to roll-out to all of UNICEF over 9000 NGO partners.

Copenhagen Business School Student Assistant Blockchain October 2020 - September 2021 (1 year)

Development of Use Cases for Product authentication, traceability and sustainability based on Hyperledger.

NEON Software Solutions GmbH Software Engineer Intern January 2020 - April 2020 (4 months) Berlin, Germany

Frontend and app development with Vue.js and flutter for bootstrapping the Doguniversity app (now >300k users) and the okourse video platform.

#### SAP

Cooperate Student of Business Informatics focused on Sales & Consulting

September 2016 - September 2019 (3 years 1 month)

Walldorf/Palo Alto

SAP SE, 3 months, Walldorf, Germany

GBO Board Office: Web Development of an internal data driven presentation tool and Bachelor Thesis "Digitalisation of SAP C-Level Management Reporting to Supervisory Board using Storytelling"

SAP SE, 3 months, Walldorf, Germany

Practise Unit Insurance: Supporting Treasury & Risk Management (TRM/FAM) customer projects

SAP America, 3 months, Palo Alto, USA

Technical Consulting: Support customers implementation of S/4HANA in onsite projects across the US.

SAP SE, 3 months, Walldorf, Germany

Business Transformation Services Automotive & Manufacturing: Foresight Markets: Develop and evaluate use cases using cutting edge technologies like Maschine Learning, IoT, Blockchain and Virtual and Augmented Reality.

SAP SE, 3 months, Rot, Germany

Treasury & Risk Managment: Extend an ABAP report in collaboration with the Deutsche Bundesbank (German National Bank).

### Education

Copenhagen Business School

M.Sc. Data Science & Business Administration (top 5%) · (2020 - 2022)

IT-Universitetet i København

Big Data Management · (September 2021 - January 2022)

Københavns Universitet - University of Copenhagen

Advanced Natural Language Processing · (September 2021 - January 2022)

Baden-Wuerttemberg Cooperative State University (DHBW)

B.Sc. Business Informatics focused on Sales & Consulting (2016 - 2019)

Ontario Tech University

New Concepts in Coputer Science | Summer School (2019 - 2019)